# Nicholas Michalak

# Quantitative Social Scientist

Ann Arbor, MI402-917-3423

□ nickmm@umich.edu

in linkedin.com/in/nmmichalak/

nickmichalak.com

# **Summary**

A quantitative social scientist with 9 years of experience using advanced methods and statistics to answer a breadth of research questions in marketing, consumer behavior, social psychology, and survey methodology. Proficient in R, Python, SQL, and SPSS.

# Work experience

#### **Methods and Statistics Consultant**

2017 - Present

# University of Michigan, Department of Psychology

Consulted dozens of research faculty, post-doctoral researcher, doctoral student, master's student, and undergraduate student clients on methodological and statistical rigor of and data visualization for their experimental, quasi-experimental, and observational studies

## **Graduate Student Instructor**

2015 - 2019

# University of Michigan, Department of Psychology

Trained hundreds of doctoral and master's students in advanced statistical methods, computing, and data visualization

Instructed statistical topics including Generalized Linear Model, ANOVA, Multidimensional Scaling, Clustering, Principal Components and Common Factor Analysis, Reliability, Structural Equation Modeling, Power Analysis, and Missing Data

## Research Lab Manager

2013 - 2015

#### Carlson School of Management, Marketing and Logistics

Conducted 75 experiments and observational studies in psychology, marketing, and consumer behavior

Regularly prepared quantitative social science research reports as well as PowerPoint presentations for invited speaking

# Education

#### **Doctor of Philosophy**

2015 - 2020

University of Michigan

Social Psychology

#### **Master of Science**

University of Michigan

2015 - 2017

Social Psychology

# **Bachelor of Science**

2007 - 2012

University of St. Thomas (St. Paul, MN)

Neuroscience